So last time we looked at a humble linear regression model with feature engineering, and now we say
지난 시간에는 기능 공학의 단순한 선형 회귀 모델을 살펴봤는데요
goodbye to features and we start working with natural language processing.
이제 기능과는 작별하고 자연 언어 프로세싱을 시작해보죠
And we're going to begin with a rather simplistic type of NLP, which is called Bag of words, which
NLP의 다소 단순한 유형으로 시작하겠습니다 앞서 짧게 언급한 단어 주머니라고
I briefly mentioned before.
하죠
So we're going to start by putting making these two very useful things.
이 두 가지 유용한 것부터 만들어 볼게요
One is called prices and one is called documents and prices is just the list of all of the prices in
하나는 가격이고 다른 하나는 문서인데 가격은 훈련 데이터 집합에 있는 모든 가격
our training data set and documents is all of the test prompts from our training data set.
목록입니다 문서는 훈련 데이터 집합에 있는 모든 테스트 프롬프트고요
Just a bit of text, and what we're going to try and do now is build models which use the text in our
비트 텍스트죠 이제 우리가 할 건 문서에 텍스트를 사용하는 모델을 만드는
documents, rather than using features that we have engineered ourselves.
겁니다 우리가 만든 기능을 사용하는 대신에요
Just use the text.
그냥 글자를 써요
Um, and yeah, one one little trick you might notice here is that I use the test prompt, not the training
눈치채셨겠지만 작은 트릭이 하나 있어요 훈련용이 아니라 테스트 프롬프트죠
If I use the training prompt, it would include the price in the training prompt.
훈련 시간을 이용하면 가격도 포함되어 있죠
And that wouldn't work because then of course the model would just learn to spot the price itself is
그건 작동하지 않을 겁니다 모델은 당연히 가격 자체를 알아내는 법을 배우게 될 테니까요 프롬프트
actually in the prompt.
안에 있죠
And then when it got to test time, it would fail rather miserably.
테스트 시간이 되면 처참하게 실패하죠
So that's a little trick to watch out for.
조심해야 할 트릭이죠
Um, a trap I'm more likely to watch out for.
제가 더 조심해야 할 함정이죠
So we prepare that.
그래서 준비하죠
We're now going to use something called a countvectorizer, which sounds super fancy.
이제 countvectorizer를 사용할 거예요 이름만 들어도 근사하죠
At any time that you think you're going to be working today with a count of Vectorizer, sounds like
오늘 카운트 오브 벡터라이저로 작업한다고 생각한다면 매우
you're going to be building something that's highly sophisticated, but it is, alas, not sophisticated.
복잡한 무언가를 만들 거라고 생각하지만 실제로는 그렇지 않아요
What it's going to do is simply look for the counting, the number of words, and then build a vector
단순히 단어 수를 세는 것을 찾는 것입니다 그리고 벡터 내의 각 위치들이 특정 단어를
where each location in the vector represents a particular word, and then how many times that word appears
나타내는 곳에 벡터를 구축합니다 그리고 그 단어가 여러분 문서에 몇 번 나타날지
in your document.
확인하죠
So each document will be a vector, and every row in that vector represents a word in your vocabulary.
각 문서는 벡터입니다 벡터의 모든 행은 여러분 어휘의 단어를 나타내죠
And the counter counts how many times it's there.
카운터는 몇 번 왔는지 세어보고요
And that whole way of thinking about things is known as a bag of words model, because it's like you
이런 사고방식을 단어 자루 모델이라고 해요 단어 자루를 들고 숫자를
have a bag of words that you are counting up, and it doesn't matter what order the words appear in,
세는 것과 같죠 단어 순서는 상관없어요 특정 횟수만큼만
it's just the fact that they are there a certain number of times.
단어에 대한 개념이 있는 거죠
Uh, and so we're doing that we're going to count up to the 1000 most common or most important of the
그래서 가장 흔하거나 가장 중요한 단어 1,000개까지 셀 거예요
And we're going to use this parameter here to make sure that it only, uh, it, it removes, uh, common
여기 이 매개 변수를 이용해 확실히 하려는 건 일반적인 스톱 단어를 제거하는 겁니다 사람들이
stop words, which is what people call things like and and the and in and it that are going to be not
앤 앤 더 앤 인이라고 부르는 거죠 모델에 유용하지 않고 방해만
useful for the model and only a distraction.
되는 것들이죠
And so they will get plucked out leaving us with juicy words behind.
get이 뽑히면 즙이 흐르는 단어만 남죠
And um, what we're then going to do is, uh, and now you can see we do things much quicker.
이제 우리가 할 일은 보다시피 훨씬 빨라졌어요
We're going to, uh, we're going to create our data set based on these documents.
이 문서에 기반해 데이터 세트를 생성할 거예요
We're going to create a linear regression model again just as before.
아까처럼 선형 회귀 모델을 다시 만들 거예요
And we're going to fit our bag of words, um, to our prices.
우리 단어를 가격에 맞춰야 해요
In other words, we're instead of using features this time we're replacing our features with this bag
다시 말해, 이번엔 기능을 사용하는 대신 이 단어들을 사용하는
of words, this vector counting the number of words, um, for each word, each of our 1000 words in
겁니다 벡터 단어로요 단어 개수를 세는 거죠 가장 흔한 사전 용어에 있는
our most common dictionary vocab.
단어 천 개의 개수를요
So that's what we're going to do.
그렇게 할 거예요
We're going to run that linear regression.
선형 회귀를 실행할 거예요
It's happening right now.
지금 진행 중이에요
It's counting up the uh, the, the 1000, uh, vector points across all of our data set.
모든 데이터 집합에 걸친 벡터 포인트 1,000개를 세고 있어요
Um, and then once it's done that, we're going to put that into a bag of words, linear regression,
그 작업이 끝나면 그걸 단어 모음에 넣습니다 선형 회귀, 프라이서죠
pricer.
Put
and we are then going to test it, so we will test it again.
그리고 테스트할 거예요 다시 테스트하죠
It's just completed running.
방금 실행이 완료됐어요
Um, so this is our function, our simple function that will try it out and we will test it with tester
이건 우리 함수예요 시험해 볼 간단한 함수죠 테스터.테스트라는 기기로 테스트할
dot test.
거예요
Bag of words.
말주변이 좋네요
Linear regression Pricer.
선형 회귀 프라이저예요
Let's see how it does.
어떻게 되나 보죠
Lots of greens there I see.
채소가 많네요
But also lots of reds.
붉은색도 많고요
You can see.
보이시죠?
Let's just pluck one out.
하나만 뽑죠
It guest $74.
74달러가 들었죠
And it was in fact $46.
사실 46달러였어요
So you can see that it's got things that are right.
그래서 제대로 된 것들이 있는 걸 볼 수 있죠
It's also got things that are way off.
너무 많이 벗어난 부분도 있어요
How do you think the graph is going to look.
그래프가 어떻게 보일까요?
Let's see.
어디 보죠
Okay okay.
네, 좋아요
Well it's looking more like there's some something good happening.
뭔가 좋은 일이 일어날 것 같아요
We're starting to see things converging around the line.
점점 더 가까워지고 있어요
We're seeing a lot more green dots.
녹색 점이 더 많이 보여요
The average is $113.
평균 113달러죠
So distinctly better than the linear regression with features and distinctly better than guessing.
특징이 있는 선형 퇴행보다 훨씬 낫고 추측보다 훨씬 낫네요
Uh, so, uh, progress happening.
진전이 있네요
There's still some weird outliers here, some some problems.
아직 이상한 점이 있어요 문제가 좀 있죠
Um, but, uh, that this was the true value and it should have been right up there somewhere.
하지만 이게 진정한 가치이고 여기 어딘가에 있어야 한다고 생각했죠
Um, but there you can see that there is a progress being made.
하지만 진전이 있다는 걸 알 수 있어요
So next, the the last of the of this set before we go into more advanced models is going to be using
좀 더 고급 모델로 넘어가기 전에 이 세트의 마지막은 젠심 라이브러리를
the amazing Gensim library to, uh, introduce this word to vec model.
이용해 이 단어를 베크 모델에 소개하는 거예요
That was uh, it was one of the first times that I really encountered, uh, neural networks with NLP,
그게 제가 NLP와 함께 있는 신경 네트워크를 처음 접한
uh, using a vectorization model, um, with, with something that is a more sophisticated, uh, vector
것 중 하나입니다. 벡터화 모델을 사용했고 더 복잡한 벡터 내장 모델을 사용했죠.
Um, and we are going to use this word two vec function class from Gensim, and we are going to build
겐심에서 2VC 함수 클래스를 사용하겠습니다 400D로
vectors with 400 dimensions.
벡터를 빌드하죠
And it's I've set it to use eight workers, which means it really hammers my box.
그래서 일꾼 8명을 쓰도록 설정했어요 제 상자를 망치질하는 셈이죠
This still took several minutes to run, and I ran it in advance so we wouldn't have to wait for for
실행하는 데 몇 분 걸렸어요 이걸 다 기다리지 않게 미리 실행했죠
Uh, and I also then ran this, and that should mean that hopefully we are ready just to run this and
그리고 이걸 실행했어요 이제 실행할 준비가 됐으면 좋겠네요
to immediately see the results tester dot test.
바로 결과를 볼 수 있게요
We should be able to pass in the word two vec linear regression pricer and see how this fancy vectorization
2bc 선형 회귀 프라이어를 통과시킬 수 있을 거예요 이 멋진 벡터화 모델이 선형 회귀로
model performs with linear regression.
어떻게 작동하는지 보죠
Well, it looks good so far from the first two lines, but oh no.
처음 두 줄까지는 괜찮아 보이는데 큰일이네요
Then there's some red, some green, some red, some greens, lots of reds that scoot down past the
빨강도 있고 초록도 있고 빨강도 있고 초록도 있고 빨강이 많네요 250개의 데이터
250 test data points to the chart.
포인트를 지나 해도로 내려갔어요
So here we have it.
여기 있네요
It looks quite decent again.
다시 괜찮아졌어요
Interestingly, the bad news is it's actually a hair worse than linear regression based on the simple
흥미롭게도 나쁜 소식은 단순한 단어 모델에 따르면 선형 회귀보다 머리카락이 더 나쁘다는
bag of words model.
거예요
So unveiling the lovely word two vec vector hasn't yet particularly helped us.
멋진 단어를 공개하죠 벡터 2개는 아직 도움이 안 됐어요
We're still much the same territory as before, and that may be because the linear regression model
여전히 이전과 같은 영역입니다. 아마도 2Vc 벡터에 있는
isn't powerful enough to take advantage of all of the extra information that we have in these word two
추가 정보를 활용할 만큼 선형 회귀 모델이 강력하지 않기 때문일
vec vectors.
거예요.
So in the next time we're going to explore some slightly more sophisticated models, and then we'll
다음 시간에는 좀 더 복잡한 모델을 탐구해 보고 전통적인 머신
be done with our with our traditional machine learning.
러닝을 마무리할 거예요
So just hang on in there for a bit longer, because I want to dig a little bit more juice out of this.
조금만 더 기다려 주세요 비트를 좀 더 짜내고 싶거든요
We want to get a bit better with our baseline models, because we don't want our LMS to have an easy
베이스라인 모델로 좀 더 나아지길 원합니다 LMS가 비트 코일에서 쉽게 실행되는 걸 원치
run at this at all.
않으니까요
We want to we want to put up a fight.
Put it's go 우린 싸우고 싶어요
So see you next time.
다음에 봐요